CLAYTON FERRIS

SKILLS

Full stack web application development, with a primary focus on front end. Developed JavaScript for over a decade, spanning across React, Angular, Backbone, jQuery and vanilla JS. Server-side experience with Scala (Spray, Play, akka-http), Ruby (Rails, Sinatra), Node.js (Express, Koa). Familiarity with Objective-C, Swift, C# and Java.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SPINGO, REMOTE 2012-CURRENT Joined early in the startup stage, filling various roles. Setup and managed infrastructure with SaltStack. Transitioned a monolithic PHP application to a scalable Scala microservice backend with client-side applications in AngularJS and React / Redux.

DEVELOPER, **RAYTHEON MISSILE SYSTEMS TUCSON**, **ARIZONA 2007-2011**Front end web development for both raytheon.com and internal intranet. Built custom JavaScript components and plugins integrated into Oracle CMS. Led the migration away from Flash to modern and open web technologies. Built the company's first mobile and responsive microsites.

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR. SPIN MEDIA MARKETING PROVO. UTAH 2006-2007Lead developer for many internal and client web applications. Ruby on Rails was our framework of choice, additionally some Wordpress and Drupal development.

ENGINEER. SOULARIUM STUDIOS ALPINE, UTAH 2005-2006
Recorded, mixed, and mastered audio on a high-end Pro Tools DAW. Required to be extremely knowledgeable in troubleshooting as every technical issue cost time and money.
Worked to serve created audio to clients across the world as seamlessly and quickly as

ADMINISTRATOR, BYU MEDIA ARTS LAB PROVO, UTAH 2004-2005
Managed audio and video editing workstations, a web-based equipment checkout system, and trained students on industry-standard software. Set up and maintained an Xgrid/Xserve system for streamlining media workflow.

AWARDS

possible.

WINNER CACTUS HACK 2015

TwitBeat - Twitter visualization built in React and Koa using Twitter's streaming API

WINNER STARTUP WEEKEND SLC 2013

Wizard War - Multiplayer iOS game built using Cocos2D and Firebase

EDUCATION

Brigham Young University, Provo Utah – BA Media Arts Studies, 2006